YESENIA BARAJAS

Frontend Developer

yesenia.n.barajas@gmail.com I (559) 772-9370 I LinkedIn I My Website

Professional Summary

I have 3 years of experience working as an ad hoc frontend developer for several documentation websites. In addition, I have 10 years of experience writing developer documentation. I primarily code in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and I'm learning React.

Recent Frontend Development Achievements

- **Docs Library Redesign** (2021) Designed, coded, and launched the UI redesign for a multi-product documentation website using Scrum-based approach.
- Header Hierarchy Project (2021) Researched and implemented a new header style for a
 documentation website to ensure end users could identify section hierarchies easily.
- **Note Format Project** (2021) Updated the note style for a documentation website to align with current trends.
- Prototype for delivering docs via dashboard (2020) Created a high-fidelity prototype for a new documentation delivery mechanism by integrating an API-based CMS into a dashboard powered by React.

Technical Skills

Languages: Fluent in CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Markdown, and YAML

Frameworks: Learning React and familiar with Bootstrap

Misc: web-based API Integration, Postman, Contentful, MadCap Flare

Work History

Senior Technical Writer / Ad Hoc Frontend Developer

Shape Security | Jun 2020 - Present | Santa Clara, CA + Remote

 As the lead UI developer on the documentation team, I'm responsible for the design, development, and launch of UI updates to the documentation website using CSS, HTML, and JavaScript.

Senior Technical Writer

Netflix | Mar 2019 - Jan 2020 | Los Gatos, CA

As the primary technical writer for a payments engineering team, I led a group of tools
engineers and designers to create and launch a new developer documentation website. I
coordinated the migration of content, approved design choices, conducted user testing,
and ultimately integrated highly technical components built by tools engineers.

Senior Technical Writer / Ad Hoc Frontend Developer

WePay | Mar 2017 - Mar 2019 | Redwood City, CA

• I managed and updated the WePay documentation website using CSS, HTML, Markdown, JavaScript, and YAML.

Technical Writer (Contract)

Wells Fargo | Dec 2016 - Mar 2017 | San Francisco, CA

• API documentation writer for various digital payments products.

Technical Writer

SOASTA | Jun 2015 - Nov 2016 | Mountain View, CA

Product documentation writer for cloud-based products.

Technical Writer

iPass | Jun 2013 - May 2015 | Redwood City, CA

• Technical and UI/UX writer for an internet aggregation application.

Technical Writer (Contract)

Fujitsu | Nov 2012 to May 2013 | Sunnyvale, CA

• Technical writer for an IT department.

Communications Assistant

Cal Aggie Alumni Association | Aug 2011 - Jun 2012 | Davis, CA

• Business writer for the executive department.

Personal Projects

<u>Personal Website</u> - A personal website where I share my work and showcase my technical skills. Skills used: **HTML**, **CSS**, **JS**, and **Responsive Design**

<u>Punchline Generating Page</u> - A web page showcasing my ability to integrate an API call into a JS script.

Skills used: **JS and API Integration**

<u>Knowledge Base</u> - An example landing page for a multi-product developer docs.

Skills used: HTML, CSS, and Information Architecture

Education

UX Certified Professional with Nielsen Norman Group | San Francisco, CA | Jun 2018 **B.A. in English Literature** from UC Davis | Davis, CA | Jun 2012

Languages

• Spanish (native speaker)